Finding Aid for the In the Life records LSC.2178
UCLA Library Special Collections
In the Life records
circa 1990-2012
UCLA Library Special Collections
In the Life (Firm)
LSC.2178
28 linear feet (69 boxes and 1 flat box)
In the Life Media was founded in 1992 with a mission of bringing real LGBT stories into the media. The collection consists of records related to the production company In the Life and the production of its flagship television program In the Life.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of In the Life Media, 2013.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9974250343606533
History
In the Life (also known as In the Life Media) was a production company founded in 1992 with the mission of broadcasting LGBT stories in an effort to challenge homophobia and negative perceptions. Airing in 1992 on six Public Broadcasting Stations, the television series In the Life (ITL) was the first nationally broadcast public television series dedicated to advocating visibility and equality for the LGBT community. During its series run from 1992-2012, ITL grew to reach over one hundred stations across the United States, as well as Canada. The television series gained critical acclaim, earning Emmy Award nominations, a Lambda Legal Liberty Award, the NLGJA Seigenthaler Award for excellence in network television, and a GLAAD Media Award for Outstanding TV Journalism-Newsmagazine.
ITL began as an entertainment-based, variety show, but after its first season it evolved into an in-the-field public affairs newsmagazine program, covering a wide range of topics pertaining to LGBT issues including religious, political, and family issues, gay rights, matters specific to LGBT youths, and HIV/AIDS. Episode highlights include coverage of the 1993 March on Washington, the 1994 Gay Games, and the Stonewall 25th anniversary in New York. The series was also known for its coverage of various art and cultural events, highlighting important contributions from the LGBT community. The last episode of In the Life aired in December of 2012.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of records related to the production company In the Life and the production of its flagship television program In the Life. The bulk of the files document various aspects of production of In the Life episodes including episode run downs and transcripts, contracts, research, and publicity. Additionally there are files pertaining to marketing and development, publicity and press, the office of the Executive Director, the Board of Directors, and series producer, Jacqueline Gares.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Production Records
Legal Records
Executive Director's Files
Board of Director's Files
Publicity and Press Materials
Development, Marketing, and Communications Files
Jacqueline Gares Files
Photographic Materials
Office Resources
Television production companies -- Archives.; Television -- Production and direction.; Homosexuality on television.; In the Life (Firm) -- Archives
- Production Records, (1991-2011, undated)
  Scope and Content
  The series documents all aspects of production for In the Life episodes, and may include one or more of the following information: episode transcripts, a small number of releases and agreements, episode rundowns, memoranda, shot logs, music and footage cue sheets, and lower thirds lists. Additionally there may be episode descriptions, story pitches, press releases, publicity stills for specific episodes, episode guides, broadcast schedules, newsletters, and research material for episode or segment development in the form of clippings and/or ephemera. The series also contains production material and license agreements related to In the Life's Encore Editions. The series may contain duplicate articles, newsletters, and publicity stills found in Publicity and Press Materials series. The files in the series are arranged by episode number when known and/or alphabetically by folder titles. Legal Records series may contain additional documentation, releases, and agreements pertaining to specific episodes.
  The series documents all aspects of production for In the Life episodes, and may include one or more of the following information: episode transcripts, a small number of releases and agreements, episode rundowns, memoranda, shot logs, music and footage cue sheets, and lower thirds lists. Additionally there may be episode descriptions, story pitches, press releases, publicity stills for specific episodes, episode guides, broadcast schedules, newsletters, and research material for episode or segment development in the form of clippings and/or ephemera. The series also contains production material and license agreements related to In the Life's Encore Editions. The series may contain duplicate articles, newsletters, and publicity stills found in Publicity and Press Materials series. The files in the series are arranged by episode number when known and/or alphabetically by folder titles. Note: see also the Legal Records series for additional documentation, releases, and agreements pertaining to specific episodes.
  - A Conversation With... (segment), 2008 (Box 35)
    General note
    Articles about notable LGBT individuals.
  - Actor's Equity (Box 48)
    Letter from Actor's Equity Association to John Catania regarding news program approval.
  - AIDS at 25, ca. 2006-2007 (Box 34)
    Clippings and magazines re: 25 years of AIDS.
  - American Public Technical Evaluations, 2007-2012 (Box 21)
  - Ann-Marie Saccurato, 2007, 2009 (Box 59)
    Segment concept and press materials for female boxer.
  - Barney Frank clippings, ca. 1950s-1990s (Box 35)
    Interviewed on episode 402.
  - Christine Quinn, 2006 (Box 34)
  - Corporate America is coming out to create an LGBT-Inclusive workplace (2 folders), ca. 2005-2007 (Box 37)
    Charts, statistics, and articles that appears related to episode re. Employment Non-Discrimination act. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - Encore Acquired Footage/Third Party Sheets, undated (Box 33)
    American Public Television music cue sheets and acquired footage cue sheets for Encore episodes.
  - Encore Charles Contracts/Thirteen Unexecuted Drafts, 2001-2002 (Box 32)
    Channel Thirteen (13) license agreements between Educational Broadcasting Corporation and ITL, with In the Life Producer's Handbook and program appearance agreement.
  - Encore Episodes Work, 2001 (Box 33)
    Various invoices, work for hire agreements between ITL and individual writer/producers.
  - Encore General Information, 2001 (Box 33)
    Program license agreements between ITL and Pridevision Canada, list of agreements obtained and needed for Encore episodes.
  - Encore Lower Thirds and Run-Downs, undated (Box 33)
    Lower thirds for Encore episodes, episode rundowns, end credits for episodes.
  - Encore Miscellaneous, ca. 2002 (Box 32)
    List of Encore stories and runtimes.
  - Encore Music Cue Sheets, ca. 1994-2001 (Box 33)
    Encore edition episode rundowns.
  - Encore New Round of Encore Series (Encore Part Two: Son of Encore), 1994; ca. 1997-2001 (Box 33)
    Music cue sheets, list of agreements obtained and needed for Encore episodes, license agreements for footage and clips, lower thirds, and end credits for episodes.
  - Encore Outfest/IN THE LIFE In The City Of Angels, 1112, 2002 (Box 32)
    Outfest film guide, correspondence regarding ITL: LA Edition, with clip licensing agreement, runtime, rights and clearances, agreements, etc.
  - Encore Reel to Real Possibilities, ca. 2002-2003 (Box 32)
    Appears to be research material regarding lesbian filmmakers.
  - Encore Scripts/Scroll, undated (Box 32)
    Small amount of script pages and credits for Encore Edition episodes.
  - Encore! Edition Official Papers, ca. 2003 (Box 33)
    Rights agreements, acquired footage cue sheets, lower thirds lists, and music cue sheets for ITL Encore episodes.
  - Encore! Legal, 2001 (Box 32)
    Correspondence regarding rights, update on agreements issues for Encore episodes, list of agreements obtained and agreements needed, cue sheets.
  - Eric Rofes, 2006 (Box 35)
  - GID (Gender Identity Disorders), 2007 (Box 36)
    Information regarding Gender Identity Disorders.
  - GID/DSM (Gender Identity Disorders/Diagnostic and Statistical Manual), ca. 2008-2009 (Box 36)
    Information re: reform for GIDs in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders
  - Harvey Fierstein voice overs, ca. 2001-2003 (Box 35)
    Harvey Fierstein opinion/editorial pieces for ITL, with licensing agreement between ITL and Fierstein; Includes signed notes from Fierstein.
  - HIV/AIDS, 2008 (Box 36)
    With report from Black AIDS Institute
  - In the Life - Stonewall 25: Global Voices of Pride and Protest treatment, 1994 (Box 68)
    Program description, script/treatment, budget, correspondence.
  - In the Life production information, 1992 (Box 68)
    Job descriptions, production time sheets, pilot script, and correspondence
  - In The Life proposal, 1991-1994 (Box 68)
    Budgets, staff and crew lists, press releases, show overview and format description, sponsorship agreements.
  - India, 1995-1996 (Box 53)
    Correspondence, clipping, photograph, and ITL segment description regarding gay men in India and the AIDS crisis.
  - Interviews with Justin Spring and Ed Hardy regarding Sam Steward, undated (Box 34)
    Transcript of interview with Justin Spring and Ed Hardy regarding Sam Steward ("professor, tattoo artist, sexual renegade").
  - ITL 301 production bible, 1993-1997 (Box 13)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 303 - on air script, 1993 Oct 23 (Box 63)
    Shooting script for episode 303.
  - ITL 400-800 production bible (2 folders), ca. 1993-1999 (Box 13)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. Episode rundowns, press releases, lower thirds.
  - ITL 400s production bible, 1994-1995 (Box 13)
    Notebook was labeled ITL 200. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 500 production bible, 1995 (Box 13)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. Episode transcript, rundowns.
  - ITL 600 production bible, 1997 (Box 13)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. Production materials and episode transcripts.
  - ITL 700 production bible, 1998 (Box 13)
  - ITL 800/801/802/803/804/805/806 production bible, 1998 (Box 14)
  - ITL 901/902/903/904/905 production bible, 2000 (Box 15)
  - ITL 1001/1002/1003/1004/1005/1006/1007 production bible (2 folders), 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - ITL 1008/1009/1010/1012 production bible, 2001 (Box 11)
  - ITL 1101/1102/1103/1104 production bible (2 folders), 2001 (Box 12)
  - ITL 1105/1106/1107/1109 production bible (2 folders), 2002 (Box 12)
  - ITL 1110/1112 production bible, 2002 (Box 13)
  - ITL 1111 episode materials, 2002 Aug (Box 39)
    Press releases and publicity stills.
  - ITL 1112 episode materials, 2002 Sep (Box 39)
    Newsletters, press releases, publicity stills, programming guides.
  - ITL 1201 episode materials, 2002 Oct (Box 39)
    Lower thirds, press releases, publicity stills, programming guides, and episode research.
  - ITL 1201/1202/1205 production bible, 2002-2003 (Box 13)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. Production materials, insurance certificates, and episode transcripts.
  - ITL 1202 episode materials, 2002 Nov (Box 40)
  - ITL 1204 episode materials, 2003 June (Box 40)
  - ITL 1205 episode materials, 2003 Feb (Box 40)
    Press releases, programming guides, newsletters.
  - ITL 1206 episode materials, 2003 Mar (Box 40)
    Lower thirds, press releases, programming guides, newsletters.
  - ITL 1206/1207/1208 - production bible, 2003 (Box 15)
  - ITL 1207 episode materials, 2003 Apr (Box 40)
  - ITL 1208 episode materials, 2003 May (Box 40)
  - ITL 1209 episode materials, 2003 June (Box 40)
  - ITL 1209/1210/1211 production bible, 2003 (Box 15)
  - ITL 1210 episode materials, 2003 July (Box 40)
  - ITL 1212 episode materials, 2003 Sep (Box 40)
    Lower thirds, press releases, programming guides,
  - ITL 1301 episode materials, 2003 Oct (Box 40)
  - ITL 1301/1302/1304/1305/1306/1308production bible (2 folders), 2003-2004 (Box 15)
  - ITL 1309/1310/1312 production bible, 2004 (Box 14)
  - ITL 1700 series production report, 2008 (Box 36)
    Production report for 1700 series.
  - ITL 1700 series production report, 2008 (Box 49)
    With publicity still.
  - ITL 1902 ACLU Web Exclusive, ca. 2009 (Box 34)
    Transcript pages for episode 1902, article and list of questions regarding gay adoption ban law in Florida.
  - ITL 1903 episode, undated (Box 34)
  - ITL 1904 episode, ca. 2009 (Box 34)
  - ITL 1904 episode - Religion, undated (Box 34)
  - ITL 1906 episode - Bullying and the Safe School Movement, ca. 2009-2010 (Box 35)
    Episode rundown and transcript, with articles referencing bullying.
  - ITL 1909 episode - Exporting Hate, ca. 2009-2010 (Box 35)
    Articles referencing Uganda anti-gay bill.
  - ITL 1909 transcript - Church & State, 2010 (Box 34)
  - ITL 2006 episode- Gender Policing, Juvenile Injustice, 2011 (Box 34)
    Script pages with correspondence.
  - ITL 2007 episode - Backlash, 2008-2009, 2011 (Box 34)
    Clippings referencing gay marriage for backlash segment.
  - ITL 2008 episode, ca. 2010-2011 (Box 34)
  - ITL Clip license agreements, 1998-2006 (Box 16)
  - ITL coming out stories, 2006 (Box 16)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. Transcripts.
  - ITL correspondence with UK television, 2001-2002 (Box 67)
    Correspondence with UK television regarding potential broadcasting.
  - ITL Encore Agreements, 2001 (Box 67)
    Footage cue sheets, lower thirds list, and list of agreements needed for encore episodes.
  - ITL Encore Edition - production bible, ca. 1994-2001 (Box 16)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. Production materials, waivers, releases.
  - ITL June Pride 2007 Interstitials produced by Maria Patrick - production bible (Box 16)
  - ITL list of on-air individuals, ca. 1990s (Box 63)
    List of individuals appearing on ITL from the pilot episode to number 801.
  - ITL March on Washington (M.O.W.) - production bible, 1993 (Box 14)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. Notes and correspondence, article, script.
  - ITL PILOT - production bible (3 folders), 1992-1993 (Box 14)
  - ITL Presents: The Boys of Manchester - production bible, 2000 (Box 11)
  - ITL PSA releases, 1998-2004 (Box 17)
  - ITL Research binder of transgender legal cases (2 folders), ca. 2005-2006 (Box 17)
  - ITL Retrospective binder, 2005 (Box 16)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. Transcript with Katherine Linton.
  - ITL Season Timeline, 1994-1999; 2000-2002 (Box 56)
    Removed from binder for preservation purposes. ITL 1100/1200 season timeline; National Broadcast Schedules for episodes 1000-1200; Encore Edition show run-downs
  - ITL Videography, 1996 Mar 29 (Box 63)
    List of ITL segments (season 1-4)
  - Jaime Grant, 2008 (Box 36)
    Information regarding partnership w/ ITL for Policy Institute's "Big Conversations" series organized by National gay and Lesbian Task Force.
  - Jim Lehrer Newshour transcript re: battle over PBS programming in Idaho, undated (Box 67)
  - Katherine Linton notebook, ca. 1995 (Box 16)
  - Legal Recognition of Homosexual orientation in the countries of the world, ca. 1992-2009 (Box 35)
    Report, ITL program list, series rundowns, and correspondence.
  - Meaning of Gay (The), 1979 June 25 (Box 35)
    Article from New York magazine.
  - Millennium March on Washington (MMOW), 2000 Apr (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous release forms, ca. 1992-2005 (Box 17)
  - Out Artists/PSA, undated (Box 34)
    List of public service announcements for each episode.
  - Out Of The Blue (In Good Conscience), 2004-2005 (Box 55)
    Press kits for documentary film. With production information for ITL "Real to Reel" segment.
  - Patricia Racette, ca. 2005-2007 (Box 35)
  - PBS report and correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 68)
    National Program Funding Standards and Practices, correspondence regarding ITL programming.
  - PBS Station Development, ca. 1996-2001 (Box 48)
    ITL internal memos regarding station carriers and coverage.
  - Pipeline Project, 2008 (Box 35)
    Proposal to Arcus Foundation for project support.
  - Public Health Solutions, ca. 2005-2008 (Box 36)
    Newsletters, articles, annual report, and pamphlets from the Medical and Health Research Association/Public Health Solutions.
  - Rent, 1996 (Box 54)
    ITL production memos. Also includes articles, and publicity stills for Rent production.
  - Sage Network, ca. 2007-2008 (Box 35)
    Conference guide and newsletters from SAGE, and other gay rights and HIV/AIDS advocate organizations.
  - Stonewall 25th anniversary, 1993-1994 (Box 63)
    Episode outline and production contact list.
  - Story Ideas and notes (Box 36)
  - The MSM Initiative, ca. 2008 (Box 36)
  - Transgender story ideas, 2006 (Box 35)
    Correspondence regarding transgender transitions.
  - Truth Wins Out (Gay rights organization), ca. 2010 (Box 35)
    Information regarding Americans United for the Separation of Church and State.
  - Virginia Discrimination - Virginia Is For Lawyers, 2004-2005 (Box 53)
    Articles referencing anti-gay issues in Virginia. ITL Research Sheet.
  - Voice Over Credit Announcement (VOCA) forms and music cue sheets, 2006 (Box 49)
    Music cue sheets and VOCA information forms for ITL episodes.
- Legal Records, (1992-2012)
  The series consists of legal records related to specific episodes and include one of more of the following documents: appearance, material, and location releases, talent and work-for-hire agreements, and clip and music licensing agreements. Also included are a small amount of licensing agreements and contracts between In the Life and various television stations and/or broadcast companies. The files in the series are arranged loosely by episode number and/or alphabetically by folder titles. The Production Records series may contain additional documentation, releases, and agreements pertaining to specific episodes.
  - Actors Equity, 1994 (Box 36)
    Correspondence regarding ITL contract with Actor's Equity Association.
  - Agreements, 1996-1998 (Box 36)
    Clip agreements, work-for-hire agreements, and talent agreements for various ITL various episodes.
  - Andersongold Films, 1999, 2001 (Box 36)
    Clip and license agreements.
  - Appearance Releases, 1993 (Box 33)
  - APS agreements and Channel 13 (Thirteen) license agreement, ca. 1996-2000 (Box 49)
  - Billy Strayhorn professional photograph licensing information, 1999-2001 (Box 33)
    Licensing info related to Billy Strayhorn. With information regarding event tickets sales, appears to be unrelated.
  - Broadcast Channel 4/UK, ca. 1994-1997 (Box 36)
    Correspondence between ITL and Channel 4 Television regarding Stonewall 25 and license agreements, broadcasting information.
  - C1TV license agreements, 2000-2001 (Box 67)
  - Canadian Retransmission Royalties, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Channel Thirteen (13) - meeting notes, Ca. 1996-2000 (Box 67)
    Meeting notes and license agreements.
  - Contracts, 1994 (Box 37)
    Work-for-hire agreements and invoices.
  - Contracts & Releases 203, 1992, 1999 (Box 33)
    Talent agreements with ITL.
  - DVDs 1500 series - Legal (Box Unknown container 980 for instance of DVDs 1500 series - Legal)
  - Fred McDarrah Contract, 1994-1995 (Box 36)
    Work-for-hire contract.
  - Harvey Fierstein, ca. 2005-2008 (Box 35)
    Licensing agreement between ITL and Fierstein.
  - HBO License Agreement, 2006 (Box 33)
    Footage agreements.
  - ITL 001 pilot, 1992 (Box 22)
    Appearance releases, clip releases for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 200-400 series (2 folders), ca. 1991-1995 (Box 22)
  - ITL 205 - agreements, 1993 (Box 33)
  - ITL 303-304 episodes, 1993 (Box 34)
    ITL appearance release forms and talent agreements for show 303 and 304.
  - ITL 500 series, ca. 1995 (Box 23)
    Waivers and releases, and Music, video, and film agreements for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 600-700 series (2 folders), ca. 1997-1998 (Box 23)
    Waivers and releases, clip license, and talent agreements for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 800-900 series, ca. 1999-2000 (Box 23)
    Consent and release forms, materials releases, and talent agreements for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 800-900 series, ca. 1999-2000 (Box 24)
    Consent and release forms, materials releases, clip license, and talent agreements for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 1000 series, 2000-2001 (Box 32)
    Appearance, location, and materials releases; clip licenses, for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 1000 series, 2000-2001 (Box 31)
    Appearance, location, and materials releases; clip licenses, talent agreements for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 1100 series (2 folders), ca. 2000-2002 (Box 24)
  - ITL 1200 series (2 folders), ca. 2002-2003 (Box 25)
  - ITL 1300 series, ca. 2003-2004 (Box 26)
    Appearance and materials releases for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 1300 series, ca. 2003-2004 (Box 25)
  - ITL 1400 series (2 folders), ca. 2003-2004 (Box 26)
  - ITL 1500 series, ca. 2000-2006 (Box 27)
  - ITL 1500 series, ca. 2005 (Box 26)
  - ITL 1512 My Life's Work, 2006 Sep (Box 25)
    Appearance and materials releases for use in ITL episode. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 1600 and 1607, ca. 2007 (Box 26)
  - ITL 1601 Inside Out, 2006, 2008 (Box 27)
  - ITL 1604, 2006 (Box 27)
  - ITL 1609, 2007 (Box 27)
  - ITL 1612, 2007 (Box 27)
    Appearance and materials releases, clip licenses for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 1701, 2007 (Box 27)
  - ITL 1704, 2007 (Box 27)
  - ITL 1706-1707, 2007-2008 (Box 27)
  - ITL 1709, 2007, 2008 (Box 28)
  - ITL 1711-1712, 2007, 2008 (Box 28)
  - ITL 1801, 2008 (Box 28)
  - ITL 1802-1804, 2008 (Box 28)
  - ITL 1805-1808, 2008-2009 (Box 28)
  - ITL 1809-1811 - Summer of Stonewall, ca. 2007-2009 (Box 28)
    Appearance, location, and materials releases for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 1812 - It's About Time, 2007-2009 (Box 28)
    Appearance, location, and materials releases for use in ITL episode. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 1901, 2009 (Box 28)
  - ITL 1902-1904, 2009 (Box 29)
  - ITL 1905-1909, 2009-2010 (Box 29)
  - ITL 1910-1912, 2010 (Box 29)
  - ITL 2001-2003, 2010 (Box 29)
  - ITL 2004 episodes, 2010-2012 (Box 34)
    Appearance releases and correspondence for episode 2004.
  - ITL 2004-2009 (2 folders), 2010-2011 (Box 30)
    Appearance, location, and materials releases, and reference material for use in ITL episodes. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL 2010-2012, 2011 (Box 30)
  - ITL 2101-2105, 2011 (Box 31)
  - ITL 2101-2105, 2011 (Box 30)
  - ITL 2106-2112 (2 folders), 2011-2012 (Box 31)
  - ITL 2201-2205 (Box 31)
  - ITL Agreements, 1996-1998 (Box 36)
    Work-for-hire and talent agreements for ITL episodes.
  - ITL Contracts, 2011 (Box 59)
    License agreements for television and loan agreements with Museum of Sex.
  - ITL Evergreen & ITLM, 2010 (Box 29)
    Appearance, location, and materials releases for use in ITL episode segments. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
  - ITL ITLM Licensor, 2005, 2010 (Box 32)